VASUDEVA SHENOY

Mangalore | 9686155629 | vshenoy108@gmail.com | LinkedIn Profile | ePortfolio

Objective

Enthusiast, self-learner, and process-oriented Business Analyst with a keen interest in the latest technological development such as Analytics, Visualization, and Data Science, with a high affinity towards Data & Business Analytics, Certified Data Scientist from the University of Texas and have past experience working with data analysis and data science in the ecommerce industry.

Experience

Business Analyst - Analytics Amazon

09/2022 to Current Bengaluru, India

- Responsible for making the category side of the ecommerce business more efficient and profitable.
- Identified procedural areas of improvement through customer data, using SQL.
- Built internal dashboard at seller level to keep the price competence in check and to track business impact.
- Maintained a working knowledge of Data ETL, visualization, API frameworks and statistical method in Python.

Data Analyst - Analytics

02/2022 to 09/2022

Slice

Bengaluru, India

- Created Tableau data visualizations for KPIs, reducing weekly manual reporting time by 10 hours.
- Improved data quality by 29% by utilizing data preparation tools for cleaning and transforming raw data.
- Streamlined reconciliation processes through Python automation.
- Conducted detailed data analysis to identify market trends, resulting in improved marketing campaign performance.

Senior Analyst - Analytics Operation

03/2019 to 02/2022 Bengaluru, India

Accenture

- Maintained working understanding of business processes and financial services.
- Analyzed large datasets to identify trends and opportunities for process improvement.
- Collaborated cross-functionally to define project scope and deliver actionable insights.
- Conducted root cause analysis to address operational challenges and mitigate risks.
- Provided strategic recommendations to support executive decision-making based on data analysis.

Technical Skills

- Programming: Python, SQL
- · Visualisations: Tableau and PowerBI
- Statistical: Hypothesis testing & confidence interval, ANOVA, PCA, Text analysis
- Machine Learning: Regression, Classification, Clustering and Time series
- · Microsoft Office: Word, Excel, PowerPoint
- · Lean Six Sigma White Belt Certified from AIGPE

Education

Post Graduate Program in Data Science and Business Analytics

2023

The University of Texas at Austin associated with Great Learning

Bachelor of Commerce: Business Management Mangalore University 2018

Accomplishments

- Client Value Creation Accenture 2019
- Brilliant Basics Accenture 2020
- Star of Business Accenture 2021
- Star Performer of the Year Slice 2022

Volunteering

Petty Officer Cadet NATIONAL CADET CORPS Mar 2012 - Feb 2017

Projects

Election Exit Poll Prediction and U.S.A Presidential Speech Analysis using Machine Learning October 2022

This project is based on 2 case-studies: Vote Prediction and Text Analysis. The first project is to predict which party a citizen is going to vote for on the basis of their age and according to the answers given by the citizens to the questions asked in a survey conducted. The second project is based on the analysis of the inaugural U.S.A. Presidential speeches. One has to draw inferences based on the analysis done on these speeches.

Skills and Tools

Text Mining Analytics, Support Vector Machine - K Nearest Neighbour - Naive Bayes, Ensemble Techniques, Logistic Regression - Linear Discriminant Analysis

Reconciliation Automation using Python Jupyter notebook

August 2022

This project is based on Cashback Reconciliation automation: Reconciliation for cashback transactions is done manually using SQL tool for data extraction, vlookup and Merging option. Used same logic and rules in Jupyter notebook and automated reconciliation process.

Skills and Tools

Python, Jupyter Notebook

OTP (one-time password) Application Based Project

July 2022

This project is based on specific application: It is the standard procedure for delivering the OTP via a text message after regular authentication is successful. Here, the OTP is generated on the server side and delivered to the authenticator via text message. The application is responsible for the unique OTP digits.

In this project Identified the OTP latency issue and analysed wait time and provided solution to reduces wait time for the OTP generation and successful transaction.

Skills and Tools

Data Analysis and Insights

Drug Analysis using ANOVA and Principal Component Analysis on College Admissions DataJune 2022

The project involved drawing inferences from 2 case studies, namely - Hay Fever Drug Analysis, College Admissions Data. The concepts of Exploratory Data Analysis, Analysis of Variance, and Principal Component Analysis are used to draw inferences from these case studies.

Skills and Tools

ANOVA, PCA, EDA

E-Commerce Revenue Management

May 2022

Python for Data Science

Solution of a business problem to identify which region has maximum sales volume, which type of products are sold the most, how much revenue does the E-Commerce Company and the brands that use its portal.

Skills and Tools

numpy, pandas, visualization, user defined functions